(忆往昔)
亚当没事吧
You think Adam's okay?
不
No!
迪恩
Dean!
拿不准
Doubt it.
也不知道卡西怎么样了
Cass either.
那个关路西法的牢笼
The cage you sprung lucifer from ...
你们可以再把他扔回去
You can shove his ass back in.
想要打开牢笼  天启四骑士手上的戒指
Key to the cage ... four rings from the horsemen.
我们拿到了战争的  还拿到了饥荒的
Well, we got War's. We nicked Famine's.
我们有2个戒指了
That's two rings down.
凑齐4枚戒指
Collect all four.
我能帮你们抓住瘟疫骑士
I can give you pestilence.
你们到底要不要天启四骑士的戒指了
Do you want the horsemen rings or not?
我们面对的是什么  你知道吗
What are we dealing with? Do you know?
恶魔病毒  瘟疫和灾祸的病毒
Croatoan. Virus of plague and pestilence.
更像是恶魔细菌战争
More like demonic germ warfare.
他们想要我们的疫苗
They want our vaccine.
需要我们的疫苗
They need our vaccine.
这被称为"急需品"  同志们
It's called "Demand," People.
现在就开始供应
Now, supply!
阁下  好消息
Sir, great news.
疫苗的试验结果
The vaccine trials ... the results have been...
绝对足够荒唐
...Really quite grotesque.
我想你会高兴的
I think you'll be pleased.
你好啊  死亡骑士
Oh, hello, Death.
你许一个愿吧
You make a wish.
我可以满足你
I can give you anything you want, mate ...
当然也包括死亡骑士的位置
Up to and including death's coordinates.
我只是想要
All I need is...
我的灵魂
My soul.
如果我们能打开牢笼
Say we can open the cage.
但然后又能如何
But then what?
如果你们引诱路西法到牢笼前
What if you guys lead the devil to the edge
然后我跳进去呢
And I jump in?
(如今)
(衣阿华州达分波特市)
格林医生  旅行愉快吗
Dr. Green, how was your trip?
收获颇丰
Oh, very productive.
我最喜爱的病人莎莉丝特  今晚感觉如何
And how are we tonight, Celeste, my favorite patient?
护士说你睡不着
The nurse says you can't sleep.
我越来越难受
Oh, I just feel worse and worse.
那是因为你现在患的是
Well, that's because you're suffering from a combination
感冒
of the common cold...
登革热
Dengue fever...
还有严重的日本脑炎
And a nasty, nasty case of Japanese encephalitis.
你说什么
What are you...
不好意思  我...
I'm sorry. I ...
你听到我说的了
Oh, you heard me.
看呐
Oh, and look at that.
你小时候没得过水痘
You never had chicken pox as a child.
真是太妙了
Oh, this is gonna be fascinating.
可是...  我怎么可能
But I ... h-how could I...
一下患上这么多病
Have all those diseases at once.
这是我用有盖培养皿
Well, it's a proprietary blend.
调配的专利混合制剂
I mix it up in a petri dish ...
你  就是我的培养皿
The petri dish being... You.
休息下  会好起来的
Try relax. It'll be all right.
你会...  治好我吗
Are you... Gonna c-cure me?
不会
No.
你就要死了
You're going to die.
真有趣
Interesting.
你犯的什么病
What the hell is wrong with you?
(一天前)
-迪恩  - 少给我来这套
- Dean ...  - Don't "Dean" Me.
我说你  以前也没少犯傻
I mean, you ... you have had some stupid ideas in the past,
可是这次  这事你知道吗
But this ... d-did you know about this?
-知道什么  - 萨姆的天才计划
- What? - About Sam's genius plan
要同意路西法附身
to say yes to the devil.
多谢提醒啊
Well, thanks for the heads up!
嘿  别冲我来啊
Hey, this ain't about me.
不许这么做
You can't do this.
你和鲍比都这么说
That's the consensus.
是嘛  真棒  讨论结束
All right. Awesome. Then, end of discussion.
这事儿没完
This isn't over.
喂
Hello?
-迪恩  - 卡西
- Dean? - Cass?
他没事吧
Is he okay?
我们都以为你死了  伙计你在哪儿呢
We all thought you were dead. Where the hell are you, man?
在医院
A hospital.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
不好
No.
可以说详细点儿吗
You want to elaborate?
我刚刚在这里醒过来
I just woke up here.
医生们很惊讶
The doctors were fairly surprised.
他们以为我脑死亡了
They thought I was brain-dead.
你住院了
S-so, a hospital?
显然  范奈司那天之后
Apparently, after Van Nuys,
我突然出现在德拉克洛瓦一艘捕虾船上
I suddenly appeared, bloody and unconscious,
浑身是血  不省人事
on a shrimping boat off Delacroix.
据说水手们很惊慌
I'm told it upset the sailors.
我得说  伙计
Uh, well, I got to tell you, man ...
你回来得正是时候
You're just in time.
我们找到收拾路西法的办法了
We figured out a way to pop Satan's box.
怎么找到的
How?
说来话长  不过呢
It's a long story, but, look ...
我们正在追杀瘟疫骑士
We're going after Pestilence now.
所以如果你想瞬移过来...
So if you want to zap over here...
我现在不能瞬移
I can't "zap" anywhere.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你可以理解成  我的电力枯竭了
You could say my batteries are ... are drained.
什么意思  你失去天使超能力了
What do you mean? You're out of angel mojo?
我很口渴  我的头也很痛
I'm saying that I am thirsty and my head aches.
我还被虫子咬了
I have a bug bite
不管我怎么挠还是很痒
that itches no matter how much I scratch it,
我的意思就是  我现在像极了...
And I'm saying that I'm just incredibly...
人类
Human.
真不幸
Sorry.
重点是  没有钱坐飞机的话
Well, my point is -- I can't go anywhere without money
我就哪儿也去不了
for...an airplane ride.
我也没钱买吃的
And food.
理论上说我也没钱付止痛药的费用
And more pain medication, ideally.
这样
All right.
你不用担心
Well, look, no worries.
有鲍比在  他会给你汇钱
Uh, Bobby's here. He'll wire you the cash.
-迪恩  等等  - 不是吧
- Dean, wait. - I will?
你没有答应米迦勒
You said "No" to Michael.
我为我的误解道歉
I owe you an apology.
卡西
Cass...
没事
I-it's okay.
你并不是我想的那种
You are not the burnt and broken shell of a man
脑筋不清而且容易屈服的人
that I believed you to be.
谢谢
Thank you.
感激至极
I appreciate that.
不用谢
You're welcome.
小心点
be careful.
(宁静谷疗养院)
这就是邪恶医生的老窝吗
So this is Dr. Evil's lair, huh?
这可比"邪恶"还让人压抑
It's kind of more depressing than evil.
这是在叫你珍惜青春  珍爱生命
It's like a four-color brochure for dying young.
对瘟疫骑士而言
Of course, to Pestilence,
这里就是他的世外桃源
it's probably dollywood in there.
很好
Great.
整楼都是人
A whole building full of people.
我们不知道哪个是人类
We don't know who's human,
哪个是恶魔  哪个又是瘟疫骑士
who's demon, and who's Pestilence.
我们要怎么办
So what do we do?
等等
Hang on.
你好  我在找我的祖母
Hey. Hi. Uh, I'm looking for my nana.
她叫尤妮斯·肯尼迪(国际特奥会创始人)
Uh, her name is Eunice Kennedy.
去前台问问护士
Go around front and see the nurse.
先生你能帮帮我吗
You mind just helping me out, sir?
她大概  这么小
Uh, she's about, uh, about that small
头发灰白  穿着尿布
and gray hair, wears diapers.
尤妮斯·肯尼迪
Eunice Kennedy?
小萨姆  即兴发挥而已
That's the beauty about improv, Sammy.
你永远想不到你嘴里会蹦出什么来
You never know what's gonna come out of your mouth.
我们到底...
So, what are --
我们到底在找什么
What are we even looking for?
他号称瘟疫骑士
Well, he's Pestilence,
所以可能看起来病歪歪的
so he probably looks sick.
这里每个人都病歪歪的
Everybody looks sick.
靠点谱儿了
Oh, now we're talking.
格林医生  旅行愉快吗
Dr. Green, how was your trip?
收获颇丰
Oh, very productive.
我最喜爱的病人莎莉丝特
And how are we tonight, Celeste,
今晚感觉如何
my favorite patient?
先生
Sir...
温彻斯特兄弟来了
...the Winchesters are here.
我们还是撤吧
We should go.
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
他们之前打败过天启骑士
They have a track record with horsemen.
你是指我的兄弟
You mean my brothers.
他们对我兄弟干的那些好事
What they did to my brothers.
我们不走
No.
现在我们要做的就是
The only reasonable thing to do here is to...
让他们尝尝被瘟疫折磨的滋味
take it out of their healthy young asses.
我们要严守指令
We're under strict orders
不能杀掉皮囊
not to kill the vessels.
如果路西法那么想得到他们
Oh, if Satan wants them so bad,
他可以把他们的碎尸再拼回去
he can glue them back together!
过来  过来
Come. Come.
好了
Now then.
如果她有生命危险就呼叫我
Page me if she's dying.
肯定离瘟疫骑士很近了
Must be getting close.
是么
Do you think?
是的
Yeah
迪恩
Dean?
医生现在就接见你们
The doctor will see you now.
萨姆
Sam.
迪恩
Dean.
请进
Come right in.
你们两兄弟看起来不太好啊
You boys don't look well.
可能是得了猩红热
It might be the, uh, scarlet fever.
或者是脑膜炎
Or, uh, the meningitis. Oh!
也有可能是梅毒
Or the syphilis.
那可不是闹着玩的
That's not fun.
不管你们现在感觉如何
However you feel right now?
之后只会更加让人生不如死
It's gonna get so very, very much worse.
有问题吗
Questions?
大家都不喜欢疾病  你们不觉得么
Disease gets a bad rap, don't you think?
因为生病之后会肮脏污秽一塌糊涂
For being filthy. Chaotic.
不过  这只是形容生病的人
Uh, but, really, t-that just describes people who get sick.
而疾病本身
Disease itself...
非常的纯洁
very...pure...
诚实
Single-minded.
病毒只有一个目的  分而治之
Bacteria have one purpose -- divide and conquer.
所以  最终
That's why, in the end...
它总会是赢家
it always wins.
你们可能会好奇
So, you've got to wonder
为什么上帝要把他全部的爱
why God pours all his love
倾注在一些又肮脏
into something so messy...
又脆弱的东西身上
...and weak.
太荒谬了
It's ridiculous.
我能做的  就是证明他错了
All I can do is show him he's wrong,
一次一个传染病
One epidemic at a time.
现在嘛
Now...
如果用1到10来分等级
on a scale of 1 to 10,
你们的痛苦在第几级呀
how's your pain?
卡西
Cass.
你怎么来的
How'd you get here?
我坐公车来的  不用担心  我...
I took a bus. Don't worry, I --
哎哟  看呀
Well, look at that.
小天使占用的皮囊  却如此无能
An occupied vessel, but powerless.
真有意思
Oh, that's fascinating.
里面根本就没有天使了  对吧
There's not a speck of angel in you, is there?
也许还有那么一点点
Maybe just a speck.
没用的
It doesn't matter.
已经太晚了
It's too late.
偶尔来个全垒打感觉真不错  对吧
Well, it's nice to actually score a home run for once, ain't it?
怎么了
What?
瘟疫骑士最后说了一句
Last thing Pestilence said...
"已经太晚了"
"it's too late."
他有具体说是什么吗
He get specific?
没有
No.
我们只是有些害怕
We're just a little freaked out
说不定他还留了一手
that he might have left a bomb somewhere.
所以拜托告诉我们你有些好消息
So please tell us you have actual good news.
芝加哥很快就会从地图上消失了
Chicago's about to be wiped off the map.
史无前例的风暴
Storm of the millennium.
引发了一连串的天灾
Sets off a daisy chain of natural disasters.
三百万人将因此送命
Three million people are gonna die.
我无法理解你对"好消息"的定义
I don't understand your definition of good news.
好吧...
Well...
死亡  天启四骑士之一  他一定会去那里
Death, the horseman -- he's gonna be there.
如果我们能在他引发风暴之前阻止他
And if we can stop him before he kick-starts this storm,
拿回他的戒指
Get his ring back --
真棒  你说的可真简单
Yeah, you make it sound so easy.
该死  我只是试着扭转一下局势
Hell, I'm just trying to put a spin on it.
好吧...
Well...
鲍比  你是怎么想出这些来的
Bobby, h-how'd you put all this together, anyways?
我得到了一些帮助
I had, you know...help.
别那么谦虚
Don't be so modest.
我基本没帮上什么忙
I barely helped at all.
你们好  伙计们
Hello, boys.
真是幸会
Pleasure, et cetera.
说啊  告诉他们
Go ahead. Tell them.
你不用害羞啊
There's no shame in it.
鲍比
Bobby?
告诉我们什么
Tell us what?
世界末日就要到了
World's gonna end.
这时候还把个小小的灵魂
Seems stupid
看得那么重就得不偿失了
to get all precious over one little...soul.
你出卖了你的灵魂
You sold your soul?
确切说是抵押  我绝对会物归原主的
Oh, more like pawned it. I fully intend to give it back.
那就还给他啊
Well, then give it back!
-我会的  - 现在
- I will. - Now!
-你跟他接吻了吗  - 萨姆
- Did you kiss him? - Sam!
我想知道嘛
Just wondering.
没有
No!
你干嘛要拍下来
Why'd you take a picture?
你干吗要用舌头
Why do you have to use tongue?
好了  我受够了
All right. You know what? I'm sick of this.
现在就把他的灵魂还给他
Give him his soul back now.
-对不起  我不能  - 不能还是不愿意
- I'm sorry. I can't. - Can't or won't?
我不愿意行了吧  这是个保险
I won't, all right? It's insurance.
-你什么意思  - 你们猎杀恶魔
- What are you talking about? - You kill demons.
那边的大高个儿在这问题上脾气可不怎么好
Gigantor over there has a temper issue about it.
但是你们不会杀我...
But you won't kill me...
只要我还拥有他的灵魂
as long as I have that soul in the deposit box.
你这狗娘养的
You son of a bitch.
我会把它还给你的
I'll return it.
在这一切结束并且我安全离开这里之后
After all this is over, and I can walk safely away.
我们达成共识了吗
Do we all understand each other?
让我猜猜  你是来找我谈心的
Let me guess. We're about to have a talk.
听着  迪恩
Look, Dean, um...
话说在前头
For the record...
我同意你关于我的说法
I agree with you. About me.
你认为我太弱  无法击败路西法
You think I'm too weak to take on Lucifer.
其实我也这么认为
Well, so do I.
相信我  我知道自己多没用
Believe me, I know exactly how screwed up I am.
你  鲍比  卡西...
You, Bobby, Cass...
我根本没法跟你们相比
I'm the least of any of you.
-萨姆  - 不  这确实是真的
- Oh, Sam... - No, it's true. It is.
但是...
But...
这是我们唯一的方法了
I'm also all we got.
如果还有另一个办法
If there was another way...
...可我觉得我们无路可走了
...but I don't think there is.
利用我是唯一的选择
There's just me.
所以除了去尽我的本分
So I don't know what else to do.
我真不知道我还能做什么
Except just try t-to do what's got to be done.
然后...
And...
卡
Scene.
你们看看这个
There's something you need to see.
妮维亚斯制药厂正迅速投放
Niveus pharmaceuticals is rushing delivery
新的猪流感疫苗
of its new swine-flu vaccine
来"遏制这场空前的猪流感暴发"
to "stem the tide of the unprecedented outbreak."
货船会在星期三出发
Uh, shipments leave Wednesday.
妮维亚斯制药厂
Niveus pharmaceuticals.
明白了吗
Get it?
幸好你俩长的帅
You two are lucky you have your looks.
你的恶魔恋人  布莱迪
Your demon lover, Brady?
妮维亚斯的营销副总裁
V.P. Of distribution, Niveus.
没错  听起来像是如意算盘打得噼啪响吧
Ah, yes, that's the sound of the abacus clacking?
都知道是什么情况了吧
We all caught up?
就是说  是瘟疫骑士在散播猪流感
So, Pestilence was spreading swine flu.
是的  但可不是为了好玩
Yeah, but not just for giggles.
这只是第一步  第二步是疫苗
That was step one. Step two is the vaccine.
-你认为...  - 我确定
- And you think -- - I know.
我用我的名声担保
I'll stake my reputation --
那些疫苗装满了上等的
That vaccine is chock-full of grade-a,
新鲜出炉的恶魔病毒
farm-fresh croatoan virus.
都会同时发往全国各地
Simultaneous, countrywide distribution.
真是个"好"计划
It's quite a plan.
他们能成为骑士可不是一点本事都没有
They don't get to be horsemen for nothing.
所以  你们俩最好还是考虑得
So, you boys better stock up on...
周全妥当些
well, everything.
下周四的这时候
This time next Thursday,
我们将生活在僵尸世界了
we'll all be living in zombieland.
(芝加哥  伊利诺伊州)
伙计  走路长点眼睛
Watch where you're walking, pal.
你怎么了
What's your problem?
这就是他们所说的"最后关头"  对吗
This is what they mean by "the 11th hour", right?
差不多吧
Pretty much.
既然这是最后时刻  而我却是个废人
Well, it's the 11th hour, and I am useless.
手里只有这把枪
All I have is this.
我拿着它又能做什么呢
What am I even supposed to do with it?
瞄准  然后射击
Point it and shoot.
我曾经是
What I used to be --
你真打算跟我发牢骚吗
Are you really gonna bitch -- to me?
别感伤于过去的光辉岁月了
Quit pining for the varsity years...
赶紧把东西装上车
and load the damn truck.
行了
All right, well...
祝你们"阻止僵尸启示录行动"好运
good luck stopping the whole zombie apocalypse.
谢了
Yeah.
祝你成功干掉死亡骑士
Good luck killing Death.
谢了
Yeah.
还记得曾经一起猎杀食人怪的日子吗
Remember when we used to just... hunt wendigos?
一切都那么的简单
How simple things were?
也不尽然
Not really.
这个你可能用得到
...you might need this.
你留着吧  迪恩有武器了
Keep it. Dean's covered.
这东西是死亡骑士的
Death's own.
它能轻松干掉神  恶魔  天使和死神
Kills, golly, demons and angels and reapers
传说中的就是这东西
and, rumor has it, the very thing itself.
你从哪得到它的
How did you get that?
拜托  我可是十字路口交易恶魔的头头
Hello -- king of the Crossroads.
可以走了吗
So, shall we?
鲍比  你就傻坐在那儿啊
Bobby, you just gonna sit there?
不  我打算跳跳大河之舞
No, I'm gonna riverdance.
我看可以  好吓这两位美女一跳
I suppose if you want to impress the ladies.
鲍比啊鲍比
Bobby, Bobby, Bobby.
你可真的浪费了这交易
Really wasted that crossroads deal.
事实上  只要你好好利用  会获益更多
Fact -- you get more if you phrase it properly.
所以  我为你考虑
So, I took the liberty of adding
自作主张稍稍修改了交易条款
a teeny little sub-a clause on your behalf.
我能咋说
What can I say?
我处处为他人着想
I'm an altruist.
真就打算一直坐着
Just gonna sit there?
真他妈的
A son of bitch.
是啊  我知道  你这交易绝对值了
Yes, I know. Completely worth your soul.
我可是个好人
I'm a hell of a guy.
谢谢你
Thanks.
这场景也太傲娇了
This is getting maudlin.
能走了吗
Can we go?
同意做路西法的皮囊
"Yes" to Lucifer.
然后跟他同归于尽
Then jump in the hole.
这计划还真有意思
It's an interesting plan.
形容的真贴切  这么说
That's a word for it. So?
别拐弯抹角  直说这是你听过最烂的计划吧
Go ahead and tell me it's the worst plan you ever heard.
必须的
Of course.
要你想听那个  我很乐意满足你
I am happy to say that if that's what you want to hear.
但我不这么认为
But it's not what I think.
真的吗
Really?
你和迪恩总是让我出乎意料
You and Dean have a habit of exceeding my expectations.
他拒绝米迦勒
He resisted Michael.
也许你也可以拒绝路西法
Maybe you could resist Lucifer.
但有些事你要知道
But there are things that you would need to know.
比如说
Like?
米迦勒找到了另一个皮囊
Michael has found another vessel.
什么
What?
是你弟弟  亚当
It's your brother Adam.
你应该已经想到了
You must have considered it.
我们一直想逃避这问题
We were trying not to.
萨姆
Sam...
如果你答应了路西法
if you say yes to Lucifer
但却未能成功实施计划
and then fail...
这场大战就无可避免
this fight will happen.
这带来的后果
And the collateral...
将会不堪设想
it'll be immense.
这还牵扯到恶魔血
There's also the demon blood.
什么  你说啥呢
What? What are you talking about?
干掉路西法的前提是
To take in Lucifer,
你需要喝比以前多得多的恶魔血
it would be more than you've ever drunk.
但是  为什么呢
But...why?
它使皮囊变得更强大
It strengthens the vessel.
可以防止皮囊爆炸
Keeps it from exploding.
那他现在的皮囊
But the guy he's in now --
已经喝得相当多了
Is drinking gallons.
你居然还说这不是史上最烂的计划
And how is that not the worst plan you ever heard?
他们正在往卡车上装一罐罐的恶魔病毒
Yup, they're loading up pot shots of croatoan in the trucks.
听着  第一辆车一小时内不会开走
Okay. First truck don't leave for an hour.
我们溜进去  每隔25英尺埋下C-4炸弹
We get in, we plant the c-4 every 25 feet,
最后敲响火险警报
Then we pull the fire alarm.
那辆卡车要走了
That truck is leaving.
操蛋
Balls!
好吧  新计划
Okay, new plan.
温彻斯特兄弟来了
It's the Winchesters.
我们来给他们点颜色瞧瞧
Well, then, let's bake them up a little treat.
-救命  - 走侧门
- Help! - Side door!
后退
Get back!
出来  快点  快走
Go. Come on. Go.
救救我  求求你们  救命
Help me! please! help!
这里面还有人
There's still people here.
萨姆  别去
Sam, no!
在这儿等我
Wait here.
该死
Damn.
咱们停下来吃点披萨吧
Hey, let's stop for pizza.
开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
只是听说味道不错罢了  没别的
Just heard it was good. That's all.
就在前面  又大又丑的房子
Up ahead. Big, ugly building.
爆心投影点
Ground zero.
你也可以说是骑士的马棚
Horseman's stable, if you will.
他在那里面
He's in there.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
你才刚认识我吗
Have you met me?
我就是知道
'cause I know.
还有  这街道聚集着大量的死神
Also, the block is squirming with reapers.
我去去就回
I'll be right back.
伙计  我脸红了吗
Boy, is my face red.
死亡骑士不在里面
Death's not in there.
别开玩笑了
You want to cut the cute
赶紧告诉我他究竟在哪儿
and get to the part where you tell me where he is?
抱歉  我也不知道
Sorry. I don't know.
等一下
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait a minute.
你不知道
You don't know?
迹象表明他就在里面  现在我和你一样惊讶
Signs pointed. I-I'm just as shocked as you.
鲍比为了这个出卖自己的灵魂
Bobby sold his soul for this!
放松
Relax.
所有交易要么返还灵魂要么先赊账
All deals are soul back or store credit.
我们会在下一座死亡之城找到死骑的
We'll catch death in the next doomed city.
克劳力  无数的人啊
Millions, Crowley.
无数人都会随时死去
Millions of people are about to die any minute.
对
True.
所以我强烈建议赶紧离开这儿
So I strongly suggest we get out of here.
你没事吧
You okay?
快走  快走
Go! go!
现在怎么办
So, what?
难道报告说有炸弹吗  一千枚炸弹
Call in a bomb threat? 1,000 bomb threats?
我该怎么让三百万芝加哥人
I mean, how the hell am I supposed to get
在十分钟之内全部撤离
Three million people out of Chicago in the next 10 minutes?
拜托
Come on!
什么  我听不见
What? I can't hear you!
我说我找到他了
I said I found him.
死亡骑士  他在里面
Death -- he's in there.
你跟我一起...
You coming or...
去吗
...not.
快走  快走
Go! go!
里面没人了
All clear.
萨姆
Sam!
看来这些东西还蛮有用的
Actually, these things can be useful.
我们这已经可以被认定是国内恐怖事件了吧
Can we commit our act of domestic terrorism already?
我们走
Let's go.
感谢你将原物归还
Thanks for returning that.
一起吃吧  迪恩
Join me, Dean.
披萨很好吃
The pizza's delicious.
坐吧
Sit down.
找到我可花了你很长时间啊
Took you long enough to find me.
我一直期待着能与你聊聊
I've been wanting to talk to you.
我得说
I got to say --
我的感觉很复杂
Mix feelings about that.
现在是不是到了
S-so is this the part where...
我该死的时候
...where you kill me?
你太高估自己重要性了
You have an inflated sense of your importance.
我的地位和你的地位
To a thing like me, a thing like you, well...
试想如果桌边有个细菌坐着
Think how you'd feel if a bacterium sat at your table
并且开始恶声恶气的说话  你会怎么想
and started to get snarky.
这只是小小太阳系里的一颗小行星
This is one little planet in one tiny solar system
银河系里的沧海一粟
In a galaxy that's barely out of its diapers.
我老了  迪恩
I'm old, Dean.
非常老
Very old.
我要你知道
So I invite you to contemplate
你对我来说有多么渺小
How insignificant I find you.
吃吧
Eat.
很好吃  不是吗
Good, isn't it?
我想问
Well, I got to ask.
你多大了
How old are you?
和上帝一样大
As old as god.
可能更老些
Maybe older.
我们俩都记不得了
Neither of us can remember anymore.
生命  死亡  鸡肉  鸡蛋
Life, death, chicken, egg.
都毫无意义  最终他的生命也将被我终结
Regardless -- at the end, I'll reap him, too.
上帝
God?
你要终结上帝的生命
You'll reap god?
是的
Oh, yes.
上帝也会死的  迪恩
God will die, too, Dean.
这太超越我的想象了
Well, this is way above my pay grade.
高一点点而已
Just a bit.
为什么你不杀我
So, then why am I still breathing,
仍然让我坐在这儿
Sitting here with you?
你到底想要什么
Uh... w-what do you want?
解开我的束缚
The leash around my neck -- off.
路西法用一些肮脏的咒语
Lucifer has me bound to him.
束缚着我
Some unseemly little spell.
他随心所欲的控制我
He has me where he wants, when he wants.
所以我没法去找你
That's why I couldn't go to you.
只能等着你来找我
I had to wait for you to catch up.
他把我变成了他的武器
He made me his weapon.
飓风  洪水  高涨的死亡率
Hurricanes, floods, raising the dead.
我远比你厉害得多
I'm more powerful than you can process,
但我却要受制于脾气暴戾又讨厌的小屁孩
And I'm enslaved to a bratty child with a temper tantrum.
那你认为
And you think...
我可以帮你么
I can unbind you?
你荒谬的想法真是层出不穷啊
There's your ridiculous bravado again.
当然不可能靠你
Of course you can't.
但你可以帮我
But you can help me
帮我卸去路西法手中的王牌
Take the bullets out of Lucifer's gun.
我知道你想要这个
I understand you want this.
没错
Yeah.
我很乐意把这个给你
I'm inclined to give it to you.
给我
To give it to me?
没错
That's what I said.
那芝加哥会如何呢
But what about... chicago?
我也可以手下留情
I suppose it can stay.
我挺喜欢这披萨的
I like the pizza.
我有几个条件
There are conditions.
好的  比如呢
Okay. Like?
你必须不惜一切
You have to do whatever it takes
把路西法关回到牢笼去
To put lucifer in his cell.
那当然
Of course.
不惜一切
Whatever it takes.
就是这么打算的
That's the plan.
不  还没有计划
No. No plan. Not yet.
你弟弟
Your brother.
他可以阻止路西法
He's the one that can stop Lucifer.
是唯一能阻止他的人
The only one.
什么  你是说
What, you think --
我清楚得很
I know.
所以  我需要你的承诺
So, I need a promise.
你会让你弟弟
You're going to let your brother
纵身跳入那个火坑中
Jump right into that fiery pit.
你可以向我保证吗
Well, do I have your word?
好  好的  我答应你
Okay, yeah. Yes.
最好遵守承诺  迪恩
That had better be "yes," Dean.
你该清楚欺骗死亡骑士的后果
You know you can't cheat death.
那么  我来给你讲解一下使用手册
Now, would you like the instruction manual?
能重新站起来的感觉如何
Well, how'd it go at the rockettes audition?
给你表演个高踢腿  美人
Well, high kicks -- fair.
可惜我没咪咪
Boobs need work.
我整晚都没理由得上上下下走个不停
I walked up and down stairs all night for no damn reason.
真是累死我了
I'm sore.
感觉好极了  真怕这是场梦啊
Feels so good, I'm scared it's a dream.
不过我想起了水深火热的世界
But then I remember that the world's dying bloody,
要喝的吗
So, drink?
瞧瞧
Check it out.
那么死亡骑士告诉你怎么用它们了
So death told you how to operate those?
全部计划
The whole deal?
是的  简直疯了
Yeah. It's nuts.
当然  可是现在问题更难办了
Of course, I got bigger problems now.
是吗  是什么
Really? Like?
欺骗死亡骑士　下场会怎样
What do you think death does to people who lie to his face?
-绝没好事  - 同意
- Nothing good. - Yeah.
你想说什么
What'd you say?
我居然同意让萨姆作为
That I was cool with Sam driving the bus
终结路西法计划的执行者
On the whole Lucifer plan.
就是说死亡骑士认为萨姆应该说"同意"
So death thinks Sam ought to say yes, huh?
我不知道  估计是吧
I don't know. Yeah.
当然他肯定会这么说了
But, I mean, of course he'd say that.
他可是给路西法跑腿的
He works for Lucifer.
他不是说他也不想那样的吗
Against his will, I thought he said.
我倒觉得是他加油添醋了
Well, I'd say, take his sob story with a fat grain of salt.
他可是死亡骑士
I mean, he is death.
没错  他可是死亡骑士
Exactly. He's death.
从大局观考虑的话
Think of the kind of bird's-eye view.
你说真的吗
Seriously?
-我也就说说  - 别
- I'm just saying -- - Well, don't.
你不是一直很反对吗
I mean, what happened to you being against this?
听好  我也觉得萨姆这孩子
Look, I'm not saying Sam
身上有各种性格缺陷
Ain't an ass-full of character defects.
-不过  - 不过什么
- But... - But what?
在尼维亚斯的时候
Back at niveus?
我看着这孩子将老百姓一个个救出
I watched that kid pull one civilian out after another.
救出了十多个人
Must have saved 10 people.
没有停止  没有犹豫
Never stopped. Never slowed down.
我们对他太严苛了  迪恩
We're hard on him, Dean.
我们一直都是
We've always been.
但与此同时
But in the meantime...
从他12岁起
He's been running into burning buildings
他就义务反顾地冲进着火的大楼
Since he was, what, 12?
差不多
Pretty much.
萨姆身上
Look, Sam's got a...
有邪恶的一面
Darkness in him.
我承认这点
I'm not saying he don't.
但他也有很多善良的地方
But he's got a hell of a lot of good in him, too.
我知道
I know.
那你就该知道他能打败路西法
Then you know Sam will beat the devil...
至少他会尽力尝试
Or die trying.
我们还能要求他做什么
That's the best we could ask for.
所以我问你  迪恩
So I got to ask, Dean.
你究竟在害怕什么
What exactly are you afraid of?
是怕失败
Losing?
还是害怕失去你弟弟
Or losing your brother?